<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<add>
  <doc>
    <field name="id">pr216_alexander_andersonaspace_ref43_ory</field>
    <field name="ead_ssi">pr216_alexander_anderson</field>
    <field name="component_level_isim">1</field>
    <field name="component_children_bsi">true</field>
    <field name="collection_sim">Alexander Anderson Print Collection</field>
    <field name="collection_ssm">Alexander Anderson Print Collection</field>
    <field name="collection_unitid_ssm">PR 216</field>
    <field name="level_sim">series</field>
    <field name="unittitle_ssm">Series II. Scrapbooks</field>
    <field name="unittitle_teim">Series II. Scrapbooks</field>
    <field name="scopecontent_teim">Series II. Scrapbooks contains two volumes which span the period from ca. 1810 to ca. 1860. One scrapbook, the smaller one of the two, is bound in red leather and inscribed "Miss Julia Anderson" on the cover. On the inside cover is inscribed in ink, "Alexander Anderson Halsey. From his father, April 1st 1872." Alexander Anderson Halsey was the son of Anderson's daughter Julia. This scrapbook contains examples of Anderson's wood engravings, often three or more per page. Some of these engravings have been annotated by an unknown hand, with captions such as "Rochester as it appeared in the year 1812." Another engraving has been annotated "I saw Grandfather engrave this in 1853, when I was 10 years old-Mary E. Halsey," suggesting that Mary Emmeline Halsey acquired the scrapbook from her brother Alexander. There is also one watercolor of a waterfall by Anderson pasted in. The last nine pages of the book contain wood engravings by Ann Anderson Maverick, Anderson's daughter.</field>
    <field name="scopecontent_teim">A larger scrapbook is titled on its spine, "Scrapbook of engravings by Dr. A. Anderson. Collected by his daughter, Mrs. Mabie, with additions by his granddaughter, Mary Emmeline Halsey." This scrapbook includes portraits of Indians, book illustrations (including illustrations from Shakespeare and the Bible), vignettes, bookplates, and business cards.</field>
    <field name="ref_ssi">aspace_ref43_ory</field>
    <field name="repository_ssi">nyhs</field>
    <field name="repository_sim">nyhs</field>
    <field name="repository_ssm">nyhs</field>
    <field name="format_sim">Archival Series</field>
    <field name="format_ssm">Archival Series</field>
    <field name="collection_teim">Alexander Anderson Print Collection</field>
    <field name="collection_unitid_teim">PR 216</field>
    <field name="series_si">Series II. Scrapbooks</field>
    <field name="heading_ssm">Series II. Scrapbooks</field>
    <field name="date_range_sim">undated &amp; other</field>
    <field name="sort_ii">21</field>
  </doc>
</add>
